翻译校对       Mam
日  听      小袖
日听校对       Syura
翻译        花解语
时间轴       鬼 忻奈
压制      娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
Fujioka? You okay? I'm sorry about-
藤岡  大丈夫か　悪かっ…
うわ　ちょっと！
Hey!
M-
Ma!!
"Ma!!"
M-my bad...
ワ…ワリィ
見～た～な～
You saw!
"Aaaaaaaaah"
見た？
Did you see?
You saw, huh, Bossa Nova- chi?
見たね　ボサノバっち
I-I didn't look!
No, I did get a glance,
見てねぇ
いや　ちらっとは見たけど
but it was just for a second,
so I didn't look.
一瞬だけだから見てねぇ
No, I did see what I saw...
but no, I wasn't looking!
いや　見たのは見たけど
い…いや　やっぱ見てねぇ
はっきりしない男って  僕　クズだと思う
I think that people who can't
make up their minds are scum.
ラブリーアイテムが何かめっちゃ怖ぇ…
T- the lovely item just makes
it incredibly scary somehow!
藤岡はやっぱ女？
So Fujioka is really a girl?
He appears to have
learned Haruhi's secret.
この人　ハルヒの秘密知っちゃったらしいよ
That's no good, huh?
まずいね
What did you see?
何を見た？
How much of Haruhi's soft, maiden skin,
unknown to us, did you see?
僕らの知らないハルヒの乙女の柔肌をどこまで見た？
Well, she was changing,
so I saw her in her underwear.
だから…着替え中で…下着姿を…
You saw Haruhi in her underwear!?
ハルヒの下着姿を見たのか！
What do we do?
どうする
There's no two ways about it.
どうするもこうするも
First thing we have to do is clobber
him, and make him lose his memory.
とりあえずブン殴って　記憶無くさせるしか
Now, now, stop that. It's a lot
of trouble to cover up a crime.
こらこら　やめておけ
犯罪は揉み消すのが面倒だ
Kyoya- senpai, how can you be so calm?
鏡夜先輩はなんでそんなに冷静なのさ
Look! His highness is in such great
shock, he's a mere husk of himself.
見なよ　殿なんかあまりのショックで抜け殻じゃん
Well, now that the secret is out,
we'll just have to discuss this.
まあ　バレてしまったからには話し合うしかないだろう
Kasanoda- kun...
笠野田君
Haruhi is hiding the fact that she is
a girl due to certain circumstances.
ハルヒは少し事情があって女であることを隠している
"Circumstances - debt"
We have no right to make
you keep mum about this.
そのことを君に口止めする権利は俺たちにはない
However, would you at least
remember this much?
だが　これだけは覚えておいてくれないか
Being a son from one
of those sorts of families,
君もその筋の家のご子息なら噂ぐらい耳にしているだろう
you must have heard
a number of rumors.
我が鳳家を敵にしただけでも
If you make enemies
of the Otori family,
the Otori private police,
known in Japan's financial circles
日本政財界の黒たまねぎ部隊と呼ばれる
as the Black Onion Squad, will be
mobilized. Such is a situation that...
鳳プライベートポリスが動き出してしまう
そんな事態は
...of course, we'd like to avoid, right?
もちろん避けたいよね
T- this clearly isn't a discussion.
あ…明らかに話し合いじゃねぇ
"It's intimidation!!"
Hold on, please stop
threatening Casanova- kun.
ちょっと　カサノバ君を脅すの　やめてください
I'm sorry to have startled you.
驚かせてごめんね
Fujioka...
藤岡
You know, it's okay if you tell others.
I'm completely fine with it.
あのね　別に人に言ってもいいよ  全然平気だから
ありゃりゃ　ボサノバっち
Oh, my, Bossa Nova-chi...
...now that you know she's a girl,
are you in love with Haruhi?
女と知って　ハルヒに惚れたか
"Kasanoda Syndicate"
"80 Years of Chivalry"
Oh, Tetsuya! How is Little Lord?
お…鉄也　どうよ　若は
Did he say he didn't want supper?
やっぱ夕食いらねぇって？
Yeah.
あ…もう　どうなってんだよ
Aw, man, what's going on?
Weren't you the one who said that
our feelings of support for Little Lord
若を慕う俺たちの気持ちが若に通じたって
さっきまではしゃいで言ったのはオメエだろう
were getting through to him,
and who was in high spirits earlier?
He said we would all play
kick the can together,
皆で缶蹴りするっつうから
so I chugged down all those drinks,
俺はこんなにジュースがぶ飲みしまくって
"Celebrate"
and got so many empty
cans ready for it.
こんなに空き缶用意したのに
And yet, what was wrong with Little
Lord when he came home today?
なのに　今日　帰ってきた時の若の様子ときたらどうだ
It almost looked like
he had just killed someone.
ありゃまるで人一人殺めてきたかのような
Please stop that. You're wrong.
やめてください　違いますよ
I'm certain that the feelings
of those of us who follow Little Lord
若をお慕いする俺や皆の気持ちが通じたのは確かだと思いますよ
got through to him. It's just...
It's just what?
ただどうした
It's just that today, maybe he came
home from school with a new concern.
ただ今日　学校で新たな悩みができたんじゃねぇすかね
A new concern?
新たな悩み？
実はさっき　食事を持って　若の部屋を覗いたら
It turns out, when I peeked in as
I was taking Little Lord his supper...
Little Lord?
若？
好き　大好き　好き　大好き　好き
I like her... I love her...
大好き
Sure enough, I'm in love with Fujioka!
やっぱり俺は藤岡の事を…
S-so what you're saying is...
そ…それはつまり
- Love trouble!
"Spring has come for the young lord!"
恋の悩み
So then, this guy Fujioka is...
それで　その藤岡ってのは
Yeah, I saw him together with
Little Lord at school today.
ええ　今日学校で若と一緒にいるのをお見かけしやした
Now that I think about it,
he was making just the cutest face...
そういや　偉い可愛らしい顔してたな
...for a guy, that is.
男子にしては
"Ehhhhhhhh!?"
So then, what does that mean?
何それ　どういうこと
He's in love with a guy?
相手は男？！
Casanova- kun,
I'm sorry I startled you.
カサノバ君　驚かせてごめんね
"Pure Heart"
This is bad.
Now that I know he's a "she,"
やベえ　女だって分かったら　余計可愛く思えてきた
I just think of her
as being that much cuter.
Hey! No peeking, now!
こら　覗いちゃだめだぞ
"State of memory due to delusion"
可愛い
She's so cute...
You know, it's okay if you tell others.
I'm perfectly fine with that.
あのね　別に人に言ってもいいよ  全然大丈夫だから
Can I... can I let her stay unhappy
despite her brave talk!?
あんな　あんな健気なことを言わせていいのか
There's no way that it'd
be okay for me to do!
大丈夫なわけねぇじゃねぇか
For her to have to pretend
to be a boy, and act as a host,
わざわざ男のふりしてホストやってるなんて
obviously, she must be in
a pretty tough situation!
余程辛い事情があるに決まっている
All right, if Fujioka wants
me to keep my mouth closed,
よーし　藤岡が黙ってほしいのなら
"I will keep Fujioka's
secret for life"
then I will keep her secret,
even if it costs me my life!
俺は命に換えても秘密は守ってやる
"Music Room #3"
"The Host Club is now open for business"
It's Kasanoda- san, from Class D.
Ｄ組の笠野田さんよ
銛君に弟子入りされたって伺いましたけれど
I heard that he had made
himself Mori- kun's apprentice.
You mean, Kasanoda- san
is going to be a host, too?
まさか　笠野田さんもホストに？
I-I'd like to request Fujioka.
藤…藤岡を指名したい
"Ehhhhhhhh!?"
What is this!?
何それ
What's going on?
どういうこと
"Powerful motor"
ついに現れたの　本物が
Has it at last arrived?
The genuine article?
Renge-sama, is he really...
蓮華様　彼はやはり？
Is Kasanoda- san of that persuasion?
笠野田さんってそういうご趣味でしたの？
W- what are they talking about?
And up to now,
な…何の話だ
大体俺が睨めば　今まで皆怯えて凍てついてたのに
whenever I glared at anyone,
they all became frozen with fear...
"Walking blizzard"
But the atmosphere seems
different today somehow.
今日は何か空気が違う
Nobody is freezing, no matter
how hard I glare at them.
いくら睨んでも誰も凍りつかねえ
On the contrary,
all their eyes on me feel...
つうか　むしろ　皆の視線が
... fiery!
熱い
"Never underestimate
the flames of moe!"
Casanova- kun, welcome.
カサノバ君　いらっしゃい
You're our guest today, right?
今日はお客様なんだね
Y-yeah...
This is bad. She really is cute.
やベえ　やっぱ可愛い
Is tea all right?
You don't mind something sweet?
紅茶でよかった？甘いもの大丈夫？
あ…　手伝う
Here, I'll help.
That's okay, you're our guest, after all.
いいよ　お客様なんだから
藤岡が入れてくれたお茶
T- tea that Fujioka made for me...
Sir, is this your first time
in this sort of establishment?
お客様　こういうお店は初めてですか
Just kidding!
なんちゃって
Y-you've sure got this down, don't you?
さすがに慣れてんな
I wasn't sure what I was
supposed to do at first,
最初の頃は何をすればいいのかよく分からなかったけど
but lately, I've figured out that
you just have fun, and act naturally.
要するに
肩肘張らずに楽しめばいいんだって最近は分かってきたんだ
Come on, Kyoya- senpai, hurry up
and chase that guy out of here!
もう　鏡夜先輩
あんな奴　早く追い出してよ
If he's getting along
better with his fellas,
舎弟と仲良くできたんなら
there's no need for him to be
at our club anymore, is there!?
もううちの部に用はないはずじゃんか
He appears to be keeping
Haruhi's secret,
ハルヒの秘密も守ってくれているようだし
and since he is here as a guest,
what reason have we to refuse him?
お客様として来ているのに
お断りする理由がどこに？
The other guests are afraid of him!
他の客が怖がるだろう
He's okay, as far as that goes.
それなら大丈夫だ
See?
Wow, look at his expression.
ちょっと　見て　あの表情
He is in love with Haruhi- kun.
ハルヒ君に恋してますわ
もしもし　菫さん　今すぐいらして
Hello, Sumire- san?
Come on over here at once!
Never mind today's violin lesson,
come to the Host Club at once!
今日のバイオリンのお稽古など放っておいて
今すぐホスト部にいらして
You're going to see something amazing!
凄いものが見られますわよ
Hello, Kurakano- san?
Hurry over to the Host Club!
もしもし　倉賀野さん　急いでホスト部に来て
今すぐ来ないと後悔しますわよ
If you don't come right now,
you're going to regret it!
See? Thanks to him, our take
today might set a new record.
な　彼のおかげで今日の客入りは記録更新になるかも
So that's what you're after,
you moneygrubber!
それが狙いか　この守銭奴
Casanova- kun, would you like another?
カサノバ君　お代わりは？
Yeah, thank you.
ああ　サンキュー
What do we do? She's flashing
him that adorable smile!
どうすんだよ　あんな可愛い笑顔晒しちゃって
That naturally precocious girl!
あの天然こまし娘が
Hika-chan, it's unlike you guys
not to go in and interrupt, huh?
ヒカちゃん達にしては邪魔しにいかないの珍しいね
There was our screw-up
in Karuizawa, and all.
軽井沢での失敗もあるし
We can't act thoughtless and
get Haruhi mad at us, you know.
僕らうかつにハルヒを怒らせられないんだってば
僕らが　じゃなくて　光が　でしょう
Not "ours," that was all
"yours," right, Hikaru?
Sir, how long are you going
to stay a husk of yourself?
殿　何時まで抜け殻してんのさ
It's in times just like this that
we need our king to step up, don't we?
こういう時こそキングの出番じゃんか
Go get 'em!
行ってこい
"Ma"
Tamaki- senpai...
環先輩？
Whoa, what are you doing?
ちょっと　なんですか　もう
If you're going to sit down,
please sit over here.
座るならこっちに座ってください
Here, if you need something
to do, you can have this.
ほら　暇ならこれあげますから
I got it for free
from the supermarket
さっきインスタントコーヒーを買ったスーパーで
where I bought the
instant coffee earlier.
おまけにもらったんです
Haruhi, solved it!
Solved the puzzle rings!
ハルヒ　解けた　知恵の輪解けた
That sure was fast. Okay then,
please try to attach them again.
早いですね　そしたら　それをまた繋げてみてください
"Ma"
That idiot...
あのバカは…
Ma?
Come on, sir! How long are you
going to escape from reality?
ちょっと　殿　何時まで現実逃避してんのさ
言っとくけど
I'm warning you, sir,
while you're there being a robot,
殿がロボット化してる間に
the situation is rapidly
becoming more serious!
事態はどんどん深刻化してるんだからね
Ma...
Listen to me,
and think hard about this.
いい？　よく考えてみてよ
If you let things go on like this,
もし　このまま放っといて
and let Bossa Nova-chi
snatch Haruhi away,
ボサノバっちにハルヒをかっさらわれでもしたら
then Haruhi's future will
be as a godfather's wife!
ハルヒの行く末は　姉さんなんだよ
Ma!?
Don't try gettin' one over on me.
Defend yourself!
嘗めたらあかんで　覚悟しいや
"This is a godfather's wife?"
ダ…ダメだ
N-no way...
Daddy is against it!
お父さんは反対だ
S- Senpai?
先…先輩？
ボサノバ君　君はこんなところで何をしているのかね
Bossa Nova- kun!
What do you think you're doing here!?
Now that you've finally established
a bond with your fellas,
せっかく確かめ合った舎弟達との絆を
what good does it do now
not to strengthen it!?
今こそ深めんでどうする
Attaway, sir!
いいぞ　殿
Go! Go!
What about kick the can!?
Go on, now! Go on, right now!
缶蹴りはどうした
さぁ行きたまえ　すぐ行きたまえ
Shouldn't you be enjoying your
youth to your heart's content!?
そして思う存分青春したらよいではないか
However, if after all of this,
if you mean to tell me
しかしそれでもまだ君がハルヒとお近づきに
that you still want
to come around Haruhi...
なりたいと言うなら
...then as her daddy, you will
have to go through me, first!
父であるこの俺を倒してからにしてもらおうか
Huh? Daddy? You mean, her father?
え　父ってお父さんなんですか
You are Fujioka's father?
As young as you are?
藤岡のお父さん　その若さで？
Not good.
まずい
Who'd have figured he'd
throw him a fastball?
まさか直球で突っ込んで来るとは
血…血は繋がってないかもしれんが
M-maybe we aren't related
by blood, but...
じゃ　藤岡の母親と何か関係が？
Then, you have some sort of
relationship with Fujioka's mother?
No, I don't. I've never even met her.
いや　それはないけど
お会いしたこともないし
Then, you aren't her father, are you?
それじゃ　父親じゃないんじゃないすか
うわ　タマちゃん　しっかり
Wah! Tama-chan! Keep it together!
He's right. Strictly speaking,
I am not Haruhi's daddy.
そうだった
厳密に言えば　俺はハルヒのお父さんじゃないんだった
Not loosely speaking, either!
厳密に言わなくても　そうじゃん
Ah, he's coming around.
あ　気が付いた
I need to sort this out.
整理が必要だ
Sort what out?
整理って何の？
lf, supposing... supposing
that I am not Haruhi's daddy...
もしも仮に
仮に俺がハルヒのお父さんじゃないと仮定するならば
Like we said, there's
no supposing about it.
だから仮にじゃないって
...then why is it that I find
her to be so cute and precious?
ハルヒの事をこんなにも可愛く愛しいと思うのは何なのだろう
Huh? Sir, what are you talking about?
殿　何言ってんの
Why is it that I get so concerned
that I can't stand it
他のやつと一緒にいるなら
こんなにも心配でたまらないのはなぜだ
when she's with someone else?
If I'm not her daddy,
お父さんでないなら
then I shouldn't have any right
to interfere with those two.
あの二人を邪魔する権利など俺にはないはず
Uh, what exactly was with
all of those delusions
あのう　今まで散々お嫁さん妄想とかしてたのは一体何？
of you making her your wife up to now?
Is that strange? Fathers usually
don't wish to give their girls up
変か？
お父さんなら普通
「他のやつの嫁にやるよりは」と思うんじゃないのか
to other men as brides, do they?
What about keeping Haruhi
from kissing anyone?
ハルヒのキスを止めたりとかさ
Is it wrong to protect
a daughter's cute lips?
娘の可愛い唇を守ってはいかんのか
"Bad feeling about this"
You know, sir...
あのさ　殿
You don't want our relationships
as they are now to fall apart, do you?
殿は　今のままの僕らの関係を
崩したくないって思ってたんじゃないの
Wasn't our family setting your
line of defense against that?
家族設定ってそのための予防線じゃなかったの
Kaoru?
馨
I don't know what you mean.
意味が分からん
"Idiot!"
He's an idiot!
アホだ
"He's oblivious to it"
He's oblivious to it!
この人無自覚だ
I get it. Indeed. I did think that
your lovey-dovey delusions
なるほど　やはりな
お前のラブラブ妄想には
lacked any sense of reality,
on a daily basis, but...
あまりにリアリティーがないと 常日頃思ってはいたが
"To think that he was this stupid"
Tama-chan is out of it when it comes
to matters about himself, after all.
タマちゃんは自分の事に疎い人だからね
Kaoru, what did you mean about
a line of defense earlier?
馨　さっきの予防線って何のこと？
Nothing.
いや　僕の仮説だったんだけどさ
It was just a hypothesis of mine.
But if I'm wrong, never mind.
はずれならいいんだ
大…大丈夫かあそこ
A-are things all right over there?
Did I say something I shouldn't
have to Suou- senpai?
俺　須王先輩になんか悪い事言っちゃったのか
I don't know. But Senpai is
a lot like my dad in some areas.
さぁ　でも先輩って何かうちのお父さんみたいなとこあるんだよね
聞いたか　皆の衆
Did you hear that, gentlemen?
今ハルヒが俺の事を　お父さんみたいって言ったぞ
Haruhi just said that
I was a lot like a father!
Well, to be more precise,
in the sense that Haruhi's father
まあ　正確には
ハルヒの父親とお前の性格に若干の類似があるという意味であって
and you share a few similar personality
traits, you being her father-
お前が父親で…
That's it! That's it! I may not be
her daddy, but I am like a daddy!
そうかそうか
俺はお父さんではないがお父さんみたいなのか
"Like a daddy!"
聞く気はないようだな
Looks like you aren't listening.
F-Fujioka...
藤岡　あのよ　俺また来てもいいか
Listen, would it be okay
for me to come here again?
いや　女の相手ばっかするより
I mean, I was just thinking, rather
than entertaining nothing but girls,
偶には秘密知ってる奴も来た方が
maybe it would be a relief to have
someone come in once in a while,
少しは気が楽なんじゃねぇかと思ってさ
who knew about your secret.
Uh, I mean,
if I'm not bothering you...
ああ　いや　迷惑じゃなきゃだけど
I'd be thrilled. It would let us
become closer, Casanova- kun.
嬉しいよ　カサノバ君と仲良くなれて
There it is, there it is,
there it is, there it is!
来た来た来た来た！
Fujioka...
藤岡
Oh, no... I can't hold back
my feelings anymore...
やベえ　もう気持ち押さえらんねぇ
Fujioka, I...
俺　藤岡の事が…
藤岡の事が…
Fujioka, I...
It's nice to have a friend who
shares the same values, huh?
やっぱり　価値観の合う友達っていいよね
I haven't had anyone that I could talk
to like this, so it's nice, you know?
こういう話できる人っていなかったから　いいよね
Having a friend like that.
そういう友達って
Well, he got shot down.
ま　振られちゃいましたわ
He got shot down, huh?
振られちゃいましたわね
告白する前にバッサリでしたわ
He got cut off, before he could
even confess his love.
二度もお友達宣言されてましたわ
And got told that they were
just friends twice, there!
That's just like being told
"let's just be good friends."
いいお友達でいましょうってやつですわね
That poor guy.
お可愛そうに
That poor guy...
お可愛そう
Yeah, I guess she's right.
そうか　そうだよな
男として生活しなきゃなんねぇのに
She's got to live her life
as a boy, so accepting feelings
男からの恋愛感情なんて　迷惑でしかねぇよな
of love from another boy would
cause nothing but trouble, huh?
In that case, the least I can
do for Fujioka's sake is...
それなら
せめて俺が藤岡のためにしてやれることは
W-we'll be friends forever!
You and me, right?
ず…ずっと友達だ　俺たちは　な
Mm-hmm.
- Bossa Nova-chi...
ボサノバっち
- Kasanoda- kun...
笠野田君
カサノバ君
Casanova- kun...
...that was beautiful!
Thank you for moving me!
美しい　感動をありがとうですわ
- Thank you for moving us!
感動をありがとう
We'll be your friends, too!
私たちもお友達ですわ
That was magnificent!
素晴らしいですわ
Thanks for the moe!
萌えをありがとう
We'll be your friends,
too, Bossa Nova-chi!
僕らも友達だよ　ボサノバっち
Let's play kick the can together!
一緒に缶蹴りしよう
I'm your senpai, but I'll be your
friend! You can borrow Usa-chan!
僕は先輩だけどお友達だよ
ウサちゃん貸してあげる
I will include a big special on you in
"Moe Moe Ouran Diaries, Vol. 11!"
あなたの事は「萌え萌え桜蘭日記」第十一号で大特集を組みますわ
Take care, now!
ご機嫌よう
どうした　環
What's the matter, Tamaki?
When I think about the way
Bossa Nova- kun was feeling,
ボサノバ君の気持ちを考えると  ちょっと胸が痛む
my heart aches a little.
That's strange.
You are her "daddy," right?
それは可笑しいな
お前はお父さんなんだろう
There shouldn't be any
reason for you, as a man,
男として彼への共感で胸を痛ませる理由などないはずだが
to have your heart ache
with sympathy toward him.
Hyper starlight kick!!
ハイパー　スターライト　キーーック！
1... 2... 3... 4...
一　二　三　四…
In here, Haruhi.
ここだ　ハルヒ
何だお前ら
What are you guys doing?
This hiding place is for
Haruhi and me alone!
ここはハルヒと二人だけの隠れ家なんだぞ
You can't go deciding
that all on your own.
そんなこと勝手に決めないでよ
For that matter, sir, why do you
and Haruhi have to hide together?
大体なんで殿とハルヒが一緒に隠れなきゃなんないわけ
You fool! It's only natural for a father
to hide together with his daughter!
馬鹿者  お父さんなら娘と一緒に隠れるのは当然だろうが
I don't see any necessity.
必然性がないな
Shh! Quiet, everyone!
し…　皆静かに
Hika-chan may just be oblivious,
yet still developing,
ヒカちゃんは発展途上型の無自覚さんだけど
but is it okay for Tama-chan
to be so super-dense,
タマちゃんは明らかにハルちゃんが好きなのに
since he clearly likes Haru-chan,
but isn't aware of it himself?
自分じゃ分かってない超鈍感さんでいいのかな
Yeah.
The problem is Kao-chan
and Kyo-chan, huh?
問題はカオちゃんと鏡ちゃんだね
I think there's someone who's
actually as oblivious as Tama-chan is
僕はこの二人にもタマちゃんと同じ無自覚さんが隠れてると思うけど
hidden between the two of them.
At this rate, I wonder if there will
be any developments before we graduate.
こんな調子で
僕らが卒業するまでに少しは進展するのかな
Who can say?
さぁな
For one thing, why kick the can?
大体　なぜ缶蹴りなんだ
Please don't push so hard.
そんなに押さないでください
Hands off my Haruhi!
俺のハルヒに触るな
She's not yours, sir.
殿のじゃないでしょ
Then, whose is she?
じゃぁ　誰のだというのだ
I'm not anyone's!
誰のものでもありません
クールな鏡夜先輩が
Kyoya-senpai, why would
someone as cool as you are
どうしてホスト部なんて突拍子もない話に乗ったんですか
go in for something
as crazy as the Host Club?
いよいよ明かされるホスト部誕生の秘密
The secret of the birth of
the Host Club is about to be revealed!
You keep quiet.
お前は黙ってろ
Next time, "And Kyoya is Met"
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
お待ちしております